<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Infosec - Category - n0p Blog</title><link>https://blog.n0p.me/categories/infosec/</link><description>Infosec - Category - n0p Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.n0p.me/categories/infosec/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basic guidelines that would've prevented SUNBURST</title><link>https://blog.n0p.me/2020/12/2021-12-28-sunburst-defend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://blog.n0p.me/2020/12/2021-12-28-sunburst-defend/</guid><description><![CDATA[SolarWinds Orion First off, let&rsquo;s have a brief overview of what SolarWinds Orion is and what&rsquo;s it good for. Orion&rsquo;s main purpose is to give a single pane of glass to look at your IT infrastructure. Various technologies can pump their metrics into Orion Database using Orion poller as a proxy. Orion Pollers will sit in your network, consume the metrics they need, and push it to the database engine. From the design perspective, it&rsquo;s a robust, effective, and scalable way of having the data always ready.]]></description></item><item><title>Monitoring 200K DNS Queries per second using ClickHouse</title><link>https://blog.n0p.me/2020/02/2020-02-05-dnsmonster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 10:24:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://blog.n0p.me/2020/02/2020-02-05-dnsmonster/</guid><description>Why Monitor DNS traffic As a member of a Security Incident Response Team, I’ve seen that the normal security practices like deploying firewalls, IDS sensors, NSM Toolkit and Netflow Monitoring. SIRT is increasingly looking to the network as a data source. For years infosec has been network-address-centric and the attackers have adapted. Today it is very common to see malware command and control (C&amp;amp;C) use domain generation algorithms (DGAs), Peer-to-Peer (P2P), or even fast-flux DNS to evade IP address-based detection and blocking.</description></item><item><title>Hide in Plain Sight: Protocol Multiplexers</title><link>https://blog.n0p.me/2018/12/2018-12-13-hide-in-plain-sight/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 18:18:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://blog.n0p.me/2018/12/2018-12-13-hide-in-plain-sight/</guid><description>Almost every Internet-connected device on the planet comes with a nice web interface to interact with. And some of them like routers and APs come with their own little firewall to prevent backdoors and whatnot. So what if one of these devices or even servers gets compromised? Where do you look at to find IoC (indication of compromise) in them?
I don&amp;rsquo;t think I need to explain why IoT is a huge security challenge for every organization since everyone at least has a &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; printer lying around somewhere.</description></item></channel></rss>